# Zach Danz

# FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

#### **MEET ZACH**

I am a 29-year-old Front End Web Developer who spent six years living in Shanghai, China. I have a diverse range of skills which allows me to bring so much more to the table than just coding. I have a lifelong love of tech, languages, performance, and learning of all kinds. Currently based in the USA.

# **TECH SKILLS**

- HTML - React

- CSS - Git & GitHub

- JavaScript- Console

- jQuery - Adobe Photoshop

Bootstrap 4 - Adobe Premiere

- Sass - Slack

# **LANGUAGES**

- English Mother Tongue (C2)
- Mandarin Chinese Fluent (C1)
- Turkish Fluent (B2)

# CONTACT

Mobile: +1 (469) 604 4986 Email: zachary.danz@gmail.com

#### **PORTFOLIO**

Available at: https://zachdanz.codes

#### **PROFESSIONAL CAREER**

# **Corporate Training Facilitator**

Zmackworks Training Group | 2017-2019

- Facilitation of corporate training in Shanghai and around Asia
- Leading English and Chinese half and full day workshops
- Run programs promoting critical thinking and problem-solving skills
- Role-play training simulations focused on emotional intelligence

# **EDU Specialist and Performer**

Jiliguala | 2017-2017

- One of the largest Tech Startups in China, with over 9 million users
- Helped develop curriculum, strategy and implementation from scratch
- Acted as main performer in Blues Clues like video series for children
- Co-hosted weekly bilingual English-Chinese podcast

# **Director of Research and Development**

Zmack Global Theatre Group | 2016-2019

- Directed and oversaw all classes in Improv training center
- Became specialist in teaching presentation and soft skills to adults
- Organizer of multicultural events averaging 100 attendees

# **Head Localizer and Copywriter**

Mutantbox, 2016-2017

- Established Tech Company in Shanghai, creating digital games
- Responsible for Chinese-to-English localization
- Social Media Management and SEO-based copywriting

# English Teacher / EDU Expert

Various around China | 2013-2016

- Executed lessons, wrote lesson plans, time management
- Regular workshops, creative marketing for centers, recruiting, and more

#### **EDUCATION**

# Front End Web Developer Tech Degree

Team Treehouse | 2019 - 2020

#### **MA Intercultural Communication**

Shanghai Theatre Academy | 2016-2019

### **BA Theatre Arts**

University of the Incarnate Word | 2009-2013